Hey, stop!
おい やめろ
Stop, I said!
やめろって！
どわっ
Cut it out!
いい加減にしろ！
Tiger?
タイガー
No. It's the person we were persuaded to believe was him.
否 そう思い込まされていた
別人でござる
Who are you?!
てめえ 何者だ！
You're not getting off with light burns for fooling us.
あたしら騙すなんて
火傷じゃ済まないわよ
Guess I have no choice...
しょうがねえ　やるしかねえか
Let's do this!
Good Luck Mode.
Good Luck Mode
へあー！
であー！
どわー うおーっ
んん！
えい！
うえ！
えい
このー！
うおっ
へい！
このー！
ぐわっ
Damn it!
だっ うおー！
へあー！
yabureta PAGE wa ubawaretanda yo
That torn page was stolen,
破れたページは
奪われたんだよ
dokoka de otoshita oboe wa nai kara
since I don't remember ever dropping it anywhere.
何処かで落とした
覚えはないから
iwakan mo nai hodo kirei ni nai soko ni wa
In the place where the page used to be,
違和感もないほど
綺麗にないそこには
yume to iu nano shou ga tashikani atta
there was a chapter entitled "Dreams."
夢という名の章が確かにあった
nani wo nikumeba ii? kako ka jibun jishin ka
But who should I blame? The past? Myself?
何を憎めばいい？
過去か自分自身か
dekireba hoka no dareka de are
If possible, I hope it's someone else.
出来れば他の誰かであれ
monogatari no bokura ga sono mirai wo omou no wa
We, the characters in the story, think of the future.
物語の僕らが
その未来想うのは
nakushita ato demo shuyaku wa kawarenai kara
Because even after we're gone, the main character can't change.
失くした後でも
主役は変われないから
shousan nante sarenakutatte tashikana kyou ga aru nara
Even if I'm not praised, as long as today is here,
賞賛なんてされなくたって
確かな今日があるなら
yume nante namae no shou wa ikura demo tsukurerunda
I can make as many chapters as I want entitled "Dreams."
夢なんて名前の章は
いくらでも創れるんだ
はあ はあ
はあ はあ…
Hey, you still can't remember me?
なあ これでも思い出さねえのか？
I'm getting tired of your chatter.
さっきから何をゴチャゴチャと
Wait.
待てよ
これ以上 やりあうのは やめよう
There's no point in keeping this up.
So you surrender?
観念する気になったか
ん？
How about this?!
これで…
どうだ！
どうだ？
その痛み 何か思い出さねえか？
Did you feel that pain?
Feels familiar, right?
俺達２人の 友情の痛みだ
It's the pain of friendship.
へへっ
That was a cheap shot.
卑怯だな
へ？
油断させておいて反撃とは
You caught me off guard with a sucker punch.
うお いやいやいや 違う！
You've got it all wrong...
ぐわっ
違うって 言ってんだろ
I told you, you've got it all wrong!
へあー！
えっぐっ
ぐはっ
Hey...
なあ…
そんな簡単に
忘れちまえるもんだったのか
Were the times we spent together...
俺らが過ごした時間って
...that easy to forget?
ぐはっ
はあ はあ はあ
Remember how...
出会い方は
...our first encounter went horribly?
最悪だったよな
いきなり お前とコンビ組まされてさ
I was suddenly forced to team up with you.
I admit that I hated it at first.
そりゃ最初は腹が立ったよ
クソ生意気な若造と何で俺が？　って
After all, why did I have to work with some smart-ass kid?
へへっ
けど一緒に 過ごすうちに
But as time passed,
...I started to get to know you better.
お前の事 段々分かっていって
気付いたら隣にいるのが
当たり前になってた
Before I knew it, it felt natural to be your partner.
We had lots of great times, didn't we?
俺達 たくさん笑ったりしたよな
んっ あっ
Stop that.
やめろよ　そんな顔 俺に向けんなよ！
Don't look at me like that!
Try to remember!
思い出してくれよ
You and I...
俺とお前で
最高のコンビだったじゃねえか…
...were the best team ever!
Shut up!
黙れ！
はあ はあ はあ…
How dare you bring shame on Wild Tiger's name!
二度とワイルドタイガーの名を汚すな！
えっ ぐっ
This is for Aunt Samantha.
サマンサおばさんの敵
えっ
どうあーっ！
Good Luck.
Good Luck
これで終わりかよ
So this is it, eh?
バニーちゃん
Lil' Bunny...
僕はバニーじゃありません
My name's not Bunny.
え？
僕の名前はバーナビーです　ん？
It's Barnaby!
あれ？　何でこんな事
Huh?
Why did I just say that?
What in the world is going on?
どうなっているんですか？　一体
お前 戻ったのか？
You're... back to normal?
Huh? What are you talking about, Old Man?
え 何がですか？
今 おじさんが僕の事
バニーちゃんって言うもんだから
I got offended by the way you just called me Lil' Bunny.
何かカチンときて
My name's not Bunny! It's Barnaby!
僕はバニーじゃない
バーナビーです！
You must really hate that nickname, huh?
よっぽど嫌だったんだな その呼び名
え？
What?
あっ あー 痛てて…
あっ
Thank goodness.
よかった
いや よかった
Thank goodness.
Um, what happened?
あの どうしたんですか？
俺が誰だか わるんだよな？
You know who I am, right?
Please don't respond to my question with a question.
質問に質問で返すの
やめてもらえます
うーん
Kotetsu?
虎徹さん？
よお ほお ほーっ うふふ…
Hey!
ちょっと！
うーん　そっか そっか
I see!
Wait, are you crying?
え 泣いてるんですか？
よーし よし よし…
There, there!
苦しいですって
You're hurting me.
照れんなよ
Don't be so bashful.
やめてくださいよ！
Stop that!
グシャグシャじゃないですか 虎徹さん
You're a complete wreck, Kotetsu.
まだ利用価値があると思ったのだが
残念だよ
I had hoped he might still be of use to me.
How unfortunate.
まあ いい 次を用意するまでだ
No matter. I just have to prepare another.
そうだ マーべリックが
I remember now... Maverick, he did this...
お前 あいつが黒幕だって
気付いてたのか？
You already knew that he was the mastermind?
ええ でも あの時
I did. But then...
Just when I finally found out that he's the one...
一度はマーべリックに辿り着いたのに
I'm sorry.
すみません
虎徹さんに敵意を
向けてしまうなんて 僕は
I turned against you, Kotetsu. I...
気にすんなよ
It's okay.
お前は操られてただけだ
You were under his control.
All these years, I was being used by him.
何年もいいように操られてきたなんて
ん お？
ん？
お！
Hey!
よう！
ベンさんか
Oh, it's you, Ben.
That's the greeting I get?
何だその言い方は
お前がハラハラさせるから
You had me so worried
that I rushed all the way here from home!
家を飛び出してきてやったのに
How did you know where I was?
どうして ここが？
タクシー運転手の情報網なめんなよ
We taxi drivers have our way of finding people.
あの…
Who?
ああ 前の会社でお世話になった
Oh, he was my boss at the last company I worked for...
んな事いいから
これからどうすんだ？　お前ら
Forget that! So what now, boys?
え？
Huh?
There's no turning back now, right?
もう後には退けねえんだろ
もちろん
Right.
Yes.
ええ
Then hurry up and get in!
なら早く乗りな
どこでも送ってくぜい！
I'll take you anywhere you need to go.
Yes, sir!
はい！
お？
Now what?
今度は何だよ
乗れ！
Get in!
Mr. Saito!
斉藤さん
随分派手に喧嘩してくれたようだね
Looks like you had quite the fight.
Sorry about that.
すいません
わざわざこのスーツのために？
You came all the way to deliver our suits?
I was not involved in the development
これは私の管理を
完全に離れてしまっている
of the suit you were just wearing.
どんな恐ろしい仕掛けが
内臓されているか わからん
There's no telling what sort of terrible features it's hiding.
Oh...
あ！　何か すいません ベンさん
Sorry, Ben.
Oh, not at all!
いや 別に
そりゃ こっちの車のほうがいいよな
We all know this vehicle is way better.
どうせ俺のタクシーなんて
ちっぽけだし
Mine is just a small taxi.
Yes, your car did suck.
確かに あれは酷い
What's your problem?!
何なんだよ お前！
So...
そんで
アポロンメディアに戻ればいいのかな？
Are we going to head back towards Apollon Media?
ええ まずは他のヒーロー達と
合流しないと
Yes. But first we need to rendezvous with the other Heroes.
Hey, you can also meet my daughter.
ああ 俺の娘にも会ってやってくれよ
Of course!
ええ
Should we get Agnes to help us too?
それからアニエスに協力してもらうか
うん？
We'll have her broadcast Maverick's true colors on TV.
テレビでマーべリックの化けの皮を
剥がしてやるのさ
そうすりゃ奴も手出しできないだろ
If we do that, he's finished.
Good idea!
そうですね
残念だが それは無理だ
Unfortunately, that won't be possible.
What?
え？
行ってきたんだ ＯＢＣに
I already went to the studio.
Excuse me?
はあ？
だから これは全てマーべリックが
仕組んだ事であって…
うちの社長が何だって言うんですか？
What about my boss?
君も見ただろう？
白い球が弾けるのを！
さっきから何を仰っているのか
I have no idea what you're trying to tell me.
ん… んんっ
いい加減にしないと
セキュリティに連絡しますよ
If you don't cut it out, I'm going to call security!
ちょっと待っ…
どうやら彼女は記憶を
改ざんされたままだ
It seems her memories are still altered.
そんな
Damn it...
We could ask others for help,
他に協力を求める事もできるが
誰がマーべリックと
繋がっているか分らんからな
but we don't know who has ties with Maverick.
I guess we have to settle this on our own.
やはり僕達の力だけで解決するしか
あっ
Hey, Blue Rose! We're heading over right now!
おお ブルーローズ
今そっちに向かってるぞ
Barnaby's with me too!
バーナビーも一緒に
おい？
Hello?
残念だよ
How unfortunate that it has to come to this.
こんな結果になって
Maverick!
マーべリック！
What are you doing there?
どうしてお前が？
ワイルドタイガー
Wild Tiger...
君さえ大人しく捕まっていれば
誰も傷つかずに済んだのに
If you had allowed yourself to be captured,
no one would have had to get hurt.
What did you do to them?!
おい！あいつらをどうした
安心したまえ 今のところは無事だよ
ヒーロー達も
Don't worry. They're safe for now.
The Heroes...
and your daughter...
君の娘も
あっ んだとお
What did you say?!
You'll pay if you harm my little girl!
娘に何かしたら ただじゃおかねえぞ
How low can you get?!
どこまで汚いんだ 貴様！
You two have caused me enough trouble as it is.
今まで散々迷惑を掛けてくれた君達だ
変に事を荒立てられても困るんでね
I don't want you making things worse.
I suggest you come to me quietly.
大人しくこちらに向かってもらおうか
I'll be waiting at Justice Tower.
ジャスティスタワーでお待ちしているよ
Damn it!
だーっ！
許さない あいつだけは
I will not let him...
...get away with this.
Justice Tower my ass!
何がジャスティスタワーだよ
ん？　ここは…
Where am I?
What's going on?
一体どうなってるんだ
Hey, what is this?
ちょっと何よ これ
Hey! Can anyone hear me?
おーい 誰か聞こえないのか
んんっ… はっ
ああっ
You're finally awake.
ようやくお目覚めのようですね
あっ
We've been waiting for you.
お待ちしておりました
Please come in.
そのままお進みください
おっ 待ってください
Wait.
もしかしたら罠かもしれません
ここは慎重に
It might be a trap!
We should be careful.
んな事考えてる時間なんてねえんだよ
There's no time to be thinking about that!
Thank you for choosing to visit Justice Tower.
本日は ジャスティスタワーに
お越し頂き誠に有難うございます
This elevator will take you directly to
このエレベーターはゴールドエリア直通
屋上展望台へと 皆様をご案内致します
the roof top observation deck past the Gold Area.
Now arriving at the observation deck.
間もなく展望台でございます
あっ
Where does he plan on taking us?
どこ連れてく気だ
まさか！
I never expected my invention would come in handy like this.
こんなところで
私の発明が役に立つとは
I thought their suits had cameras.
でもヒーロースーツにだって
カメラぐらい付いてんだろ
Why bother using this?
何で わざわざ こんなもん
Look.
いいか 通常ヒーロー同士の情報伝達は
インターセプション等の問題回避のため
Communications between Heroes are relayed and overseen
using a specially developed private network.
独自開発された
プライベートネットワークを経由し
We use this to prevent information from being intercepted.
コントロールしている
先程からネットワークへ
アクセス不能になっているのをみると
I've been unable to access that network for a while now,
恐らくマーべリックが
シーズしていると思われる
which means Maverick has seized it.
Are you following me?
ここまでいいか？
Not at all.
いや 全然
Like I said!
だ か ら！
Communications between Heroes are...
通常ヒーロー同士の情報伝達は…
In other words!
とにかく！
スーツのカメラじゃ見れねえって事だな
We can't see what's going on through the suit's camera, right?
That's right.
そう言う事だ
このまま中の様子が わかれば
If we can find out what's going on inside,
we may be able to help rescue the other Heroes.
ヒーロー達の救出の手助けが
できるかもしれん
Kaede! Where are you?! Kaede!
楓！　どこだ楓！
虎徹さん 落ち着いて！
Kotetsu, calm down.
落ち着いてなんていられる訳ねえだろ！
How can I calm down?!
んえっ 俺のせいで楓は おっ
Kaede's in danger because of me!
Hey!
おい 楓をどこにやった？
Where have you taken Kaede?
気を付けてください
相手はどんなＮＥＸＴ能力か
Be careful.
We don't know what kind of NEXT we're facing.
Don't just stand there.
黙ってねえで 答えろよ！
Answer me!
あおっ
Hey!
おい！　何なんだよこれ
What is this?
This guy is...
こいつ
A robot...
ロボット
Are you surprised?
驚きましたか
お久しぶりです　バーナビー君
It's been a while, Barnaby.
You're...
お前は！
ふっはっはっはっ
I suppose you never expected to run into me again like this.
こんなかたちで再会するとは
思ってもみなかったでしょうね
うるせえ！
Shut up!
Maverick...
マーべリック
楓はどうした　無事なんだろうな
Where is Kaede? She'd better be all right!
You should be more worried about yourself.
他人の事ではなく
自分の心配をしたまえ
んだとお
What?!
You really think you'd leave here alive?
無事に帰れると思っているのか
I'll crush this mechanical freak in an instant!
こんなメカ野郎 すぐにぶっ壊してやる
Oh? You had such a difficult time fighting Cis.
ほう シス相手に
あんなに苦戦していた君がね
Ｈ01の能力は それまでとは
比べ物にならぬ程 進化を遂げています
The new H-01's power has been developed far beyond that.
Even with their combined might,
現に他のヒーロー達が束になっても
none of the Heroes were able to put a scratch on him.
傷１つ付ける事が
できなかったのですから
えっ
What are you going to do? Now's your chance to run.
どうします？
逃げ出すのなら今のうちですよ
ふざけた事ぬかしてんじゃねえ
Enough of this nonsense!
That idiot!
あのバカ！
This can't be!
そんな！
ありえない 戦闘用アンドロイドだと！
Impossible. A battle android?
I was impressed with the technology
例のアンドロイド事件で
私は彼の技術に感銘を受けてね
he employed during the android incident.
So I provided Dr. Rotwang with this facility
ドクターロトワングにこの施設を提供し
思う存分研究に没頭してもらった
and let him work to his heart's content.
The result is H-01!
そして完成したのがＨ01！
I've finally created an ultimate being
とうとう私は人類の頂点に立つ
最強の存在を作りあげたのです！
that stands above the human race!
貴様ら 一体何を企んでいる
What are you guys planning to do?!
ふんっ 気付いたんだよ
I've realized something.
アンドロイドこそが
完全なる正義のかたちだとね
Androids are the perfect embodiment of justice.
H-01 will replace all of you NEXT,
Ｈ01は君達ＮＥＸＴに代わり
and will be Heroes in this city.
ヒーローとしてこの街に君臨する
A new age will begin!
新たな時代が到来するのだ！
You call this thing a Hero?
こいつがヒーローだと
Don't you think it's wonderful, Barnaby?
素晴らしいと思わないか バーナビー君
The day when androids will be useful to humans
アンドロイドが
人間の役に立つ日が来たのですよ
has finally come!
Your parents' dream will come true!
ご両親の夢が叶えられるんです！
ふざけるな！
You've got to be kidding me!
You can fight him together if you want.
さあ 二人掛かりで構いません
The data from this battle will be used for future reference.
データは今後の参考に
させて頂きますから
Ｈ01を倒さぬ限り君達は
何も守る事はできない
Unless you defeat H-01, you cannot protect anything.
The people of this city, your friends, or your daughter.
市民も 仲間も 君の娘も
あっ！
Poor thing.
可哀想にねえ
こんな父親を持ってしまったばかりに
This would have never happened to her
if she didn't have you for a father.
Kaede... I swear I'll protect you.
楓 俺が必ず守ってやるからな
And the big man in the mountain
山の大男は村の人達を ずーっと
ずーっと 守ってあげましたとさ
protected the villagers forever and ever.
The end.
もう一回 もう一回！
One more time. One more time.
あはっ またか？
Again?
あはっ
What's wrong?
何？
あなたの事は私達がずーっと
ずーっと 守ってあげるからね
We're going to protect you forever and ever.
I won't let you have your way anymore.
これ以上 お前の好きにはさせない
You're finally awake.
ようやくお目覚めのようですね
Who are you?
誰よ あんた
Where are the others? Where is Kaede?!
他のみんなは？　楓ちゃんはどこ！
The girl is safe, but as for the others...
少女は無事ですが みなさんは
あっ
おっ 大丈夫か諸君！
Ah, is everyone all right?
What in the world is going on?
どうなってんのよ 一体！
I remember being defeated by Mr. Tiger's imposter, and...
僕達 確かタイガーさんの偽物に
Hey, let us out of here!
おい てめえ ここから出しやがれ！
Silence, freaks!
黙れ化けもの！
お前達のような人間のなりそこないには
檻の中がお似合いなんですよ
You sub-humans deserve to be in cages!
なんだとお！
What did you say?!
ＮＥＸＴ差別者か
He's a NEXT hater...
Your era has come to an end!
貴様らが もてはやされる時代は
終わったんです
さあ Ｈ01に新たなヒーローの座を
譲って頂きましょうか
Now surrender your title as Heroes to H-01, the new Hero!
えっ
H-01? You mean that fake Tiger?
Ｈ01って あの偽タイガー？
You've got to be kidding me! That thing could never replace us!
ふざけるな！
あんな奴に
俺らの代わりが務まるはずがねーだろ！
How funny to hear that from someone
なす術も無くやられた君達が
よくそんな事 言えますね
who was defeated so easily.
No matter how strong that thing is,
いくら強くたって
命令でしか動けないアンドロイドなんて
androids are just weapons that only move on command!
ただの戦闘兵器だよ！
それの何が悪い
What's wrong with that?
Listen, you... Don't underestimate Heroes.
あんたね
ヒーローなめてんじゃないわよ
人々の小さな悲鳴に耳を傾ける
時には悪人に語りかける
We listen to the cries of the people.
We even help criminals redeem themselves.
救いの手を差し伸べる
アンドロイドにそれができるのか
Can an android do that?
That's right!
そうだよ
心を持っている人間だからこそ
ヒーローが務まるんだ！
We can be Heroes because we're humans with hearts!
I couldn't have been a Hero alone.
１人じゃヒーローなんかできなかった
I was able to come this far because of the bond
みんなとの絆があったからこそ
ここまで やってこられたの！
I had with my friends.
ふんっ やはり戯言を
ならば見せてみろ
What nonsense.
In that case, show me.
Prove to me how wonderful this heart you speak of really is.
君らの言う心が
どんなに素晴らしいものなのか
証明してもらおうじゃないですか
どう言う事？
What do you mean?
Sadly, you're all going to die.
残念ながら
今のままでは君達は死ぬ運命にある
The bombs attached to your necks are going to explode.
首に着いたその爆弾が爆発してね
But I'll save just one of you. The quickest one wins.
ただし 君達の中で１人だけ命を
助けてあげましょう　早いもの勝ち
If you want to be saved,
助かりたければ首輪に設置されている
解除スイッチを押したまえ
flip the deactivation switch on your collar.
スイッチを押した瞬間！
他の奴らの爆弾は爆発するがね
However, once you do, everyone else will blow up.
You have until Tiger and Barnaby are defeated by H-01.
制限時間はタイガーアンドバーナビーが
Ｈ01に倒されるまで
The moment they lose,
敗北した瞬間
誰かがスイッチを押していなくても
everyone will blow up even if no one has ﬂipped their switch.
君達全員の爆弾はドカーン！
おーっと 変な事は考えるな
And, don't get any funny ideas.
少しでもその気味悪い能力を
使う素振りをみせたら爆発させます
If I see you trying to use your creepy powers,
I'll blow you up!
So what now?
さあ どうする？　この状況でも
くだらない絆を信じるんですか？
Still planning to believe in your silly bonds?
誰かに裏切られる前に裏切ったほうが
賢明ではないですかね
Wouldn't it be wiser to betray the others
before someone betrays you, Heroes?
ヒーローさん
The moment that Tiger and Barnaby's fight begins,
タイガーアンドバーナビーが
戦闘を開始した瞬間
あなた達の戦いも始まるのです
your fight begins as well.
うっははは あははは…
あっ ちょっと！
Hey!
Guys?
みんな
Let's go.
行くぞ
Right.
ええ
灰色に染まる街の片隅で
hai iro ni somaru machi no katasumi de souzou dake no yume wo miteita
In an obscure corner of the ashen city, I was having a surreal dream.
想像だけの夢をみていた
存在する事の意味を
sonzai suru koto no imi wo nantonaku kangaehajimeta
I started to think about the meaning of existence.
なんとなく考え始めた
But I never know
BUT, I NEVER KNOW.
But, I never know.
myself＆夢＆
MYSELF AND yume AND TRUE AND ANYMORE
Myself & dreams & truth & anymore.
true＆Anymore
もう… もっと…
mou... motto...
At all...
こんな世界で私に聞いたの
konna sekai de watashi ni kita no ittai nani ga dekiru no ka wo
I asked myself what one can do in a world like this.
一体何が出来るのかを
あなたの笑顔が教えてくれたような
anata no egao ga oshiete kureta youna sonna kigashita kara
And I felt that your smiling face could teach me the answer.
そんな気がしたから
光を見つけたような
hikari wo mitsuketa youna itami ni furerareru
And enabled me to be touched by the pain of finding light.
痛みに触れられる
そう そんな気がした
sou, sonna kigashita
Yes, that was the feeling.
人は皆儚い夢を
hito wa mina hakanai yume wo kono te ni ireru tame ni
In pursuing their fleeting dreams,
この手に入れる為に
永遠の真実さえ
eien no shinjitsu sae miushinau
people lose sight of the eternal truth.
見失う
消えない悲しい明日に
kienai kanashii asu ni hikari wo kureta no wa daredemo naku tatta hitori
No one made me realize that there is a light that never dims but you,
光をくれたのは
誰でもなく たった一人
過去も未来も
shinjitai
I want to believe.
分かち合えるずっと
kako mo mirai mo wakachiaeru zutto
always sharing the past and the future.
はーい！　TIGER ＆ BUNNYの
平熱は35度7分のほう バーナビーです
Hi! I'm Barnaby, the member of Tiger & Bunny
who has a normal body temperature of 35.7 degrees Celsius!
よーし こうなったら僕達が
何だこいつ！　ふあーっ！
All right, we're going to...
What's with this guy?
次回 TIGER ＆ BUNNY
Nothing vantured nothing gained
Next time on Tiger & Bunny:
See you！
See you!